Guide to the Mead Westvaco Research Reports
Mead Westvaco Research Reports
1945 2007
Westvaco Corporation
MeadWestvaco (Firm)
Mead Corporation
MC 00496
This collection contains research reports, under various names, for the various research centers, laboratories, and experimental forests of MeadWestvaco and its predecessor companies. The reports are grouped together by facility and then by title. Most of the reports have been assigned reference numbers by the company. There is a donor-created list of box contents filed in cartons 1-12.
MeadWestvaco originated in two separate companies. The Mead Paper Company had its beginnings in 1846, and the West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company (Westvaco) in 1888. The companies produced paper and packaging products, and they maintained research forests in several states (mostly in the American South) for the development of pulp for these products. The two companies merged to become MeadWestvaco in 2002, and it became known as the MWV Corporation in 2011. Some of the research conducted by these companies involved faculty from North Carolina State University.
19.5 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of the MWV Corporation, 2013 (Accession 2013.0281)
Materials arranged in the order received. This collection has not yet received full archival processing. There is a donor-created list of box contents filed in cartons 1-12.
MeadWestvaco originated in two separate companies. The Mead Paper Company had its beginnings in 1846, and the West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company (Westvaco) in 1888. The companies produced paper and packaging products, and they maintained research forests in several states (mostly in the American South) for the development of pulp for these products. The two companies merged to become MeadWestvaco in 2002, and it became known as the MWV Corporation in 2011. Some of the research conducted by these companies involved faculty from North Carolina State University.
This collection contains research reports, under various names, for the various research centers, laboratories, and experimental forests of MeadWestvaco and its predecessor companies. The reports are grouped together by facility and then by title. Most reports have been assigned reference numbers by the company. There is a donor-created list of box contents filed in cartons 1-12.
Mead Corporation; Westvaco Corporation; Westvaco Corporation; MeadWestvaco (Firm); MeadWestvaco (Firm); Mead Corporation; Forests and forestry; United States Paper industry; United States Forests and forestry Economic aspects; United States Wood products; Research Forest management
- WestVaco Experimental Forest, Research News & Notes, 1-90, 1947 1959 (Carton 1)
- Central Information Center, Charlottesville Center, Forest Research, South Carolina Research Center, and West Virginia Research Center: Information Sheets, 1978 2001 (Carton 1)
- Appalachian Experimental Project, North Carolina Research Project: Research News and Notes, A-1 to A-42, 1948 1959 (Carton 2)
- Southern Region Note, SRN 1-98 to SRN 1-03 [these are not listed in container list in carton], 1998 2003 (Carton 2)
- Forest Science Laboratory, Technical Memoranda, TM-88-1 to TM-93-15, 1988 1993 (Carton 3)
  Summerville (S.C.)
- Forest Science Laboratory, Technical Memoranda, TM-94-1 to TM-06-6, 1994 2006 (Carton 4)
- Forest Science Laboratory, Research Reports, RR 1 to RR 135, 1981 1992 (Carton 5)
- Forest Science Laboratory: Research Reports, RR 136 to RR 241, 1992 2007 (Carton 6)
- Central Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 - 39, 1971 2000 (Carton 7)
- Charlottesville Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 85, 1959 1989 (Carton 7)
- Coudersport Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 7, 1959 1966 (Carton 8)
- Manteo Research Center: Research Reports RR 14 to RR 48, 1959 1972 (Carton 8)
- North Carolina Woodlands Research / North Carolina Research Project, Reports NC-1 to NC-6, 1955 1958 (Carton 8)
- South Carolina Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 35, 1976 1982 (Carton 8)
- Hancock Research Center and Parkersburg Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 32, 1960 1970 (Carton 9)
- Winnsboro Research Center and Summerville Research Center: Research Reports, 1960 1981 (Carton 9)
- West Virginia Research Center, Forest Science Laboratory, and Central Forest Research Center: Research Reports, 1976 1982 (Carton 10)
- Appalachian / West Virginia Research Center: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 101, 1975 2001 (Carton 10)
- Summerville Research Center, Land Management: Research Reports RR 1 to RR 63, 1960 1972 (Carton 11)
- WestVaco Experimental Forest, Research Reports 90 - 143, 1959 1968 (Carton 11)
- Summerville Land Management, Mechanical Engineering, and Production Engineering: Research Reports, 1964 1976 (Carton 11)
- WestVaco Experimental Forest: Research Reports WR-1 to WR-27 and RR 144 to RR 166, 1946 - 1958, 1968 - 1976; 1946 1958 (Carton 12)
- Appalachian Research / Experimental Project: Reports (some include photos); Covington Reports CRL-95-71 to CRL-97-109 [these are not listed in container list in carton], 1945 - 1975, 1995 - 1997; 1945 1957 (Carton 12)
- Miscellaneous Reports [these are not listed in container list in carton], 1968 1991 (Carton 12)
- For various locations: Research News and Notes, Reports, Research Reports [these are not listed in container list in carton]; also this carton contains a binder with indexes for reports in other cartons., 1949 1986 (Carton 13)